





caio@viotti.me





I'm a UX Engineer with 7 years of full-time experience in Front-End Software Engineering and UI/UX Design, specialized in crafting and implementing product-driven user experiences. Proficient in modern JavaScript development and tooling, mainly with Vue, but wellacquainted with React and other frameworks. Regarded as a CSS wizard and expert at designing directly using code with pixel perfection.

### Skills

#### Tech/Aaile

### 

Responsive Front-End software web development, Cross-browser compatibility, JavaScript, Vue, Nuxt, Vuex, JSON, StoryBook, Technical documentation, CSS, SCSS, PostCSS. BEM, CSS-in-JS, Styled Components, HTML, Template engines, Code reviewing, Bash, scripting, Linux, MacOs, Scrum, Kanban, Confluence, Trello, Jira, ClickUp

#### 

Unit testing, Jest, Cypress, Testing-Library, Web accessibility, WAI-ARIA, Build tools, Webpack, API Integration, A/B Testing, SEO, jQuery

#### M Familiar

React, Astro, Vite, Tailwind, Enzyme, Web performance, Profiling, Python, Django, Ruby on Rails, Backend Development

#### UI/UX

### ♥ Proficient

UI Design, UI Patterns, Responsive design, Design systems, Microinteractions, Prototyping, User testing, Figma, FigJam, Miro, Whimsical, Invision

### A Intermediate

Micro-copy, UX writing, Design Thinking, User research, Workshop facilitation, LDJs, Design Sprints

### 

Brand design, Graphic design

### Soft skills

Growth-mindset, Passionate, Productdriven, Detail-oriented, Remote-first best practices, Async & sync clear communication

# Education

B.Sc.(Ed) Computer Science University of Brasilia Top 10 in Brazil 50% completed (not pursuing)

## Experience

Founding UX Engineer @ Zazos (Y Combinator S21)

- Managed and developed the company's Design System from scratch, creating 20 tailored components for optimal DX/UX with Vue + StoryBook, cutting 70% of unstructured UI lib code
- Led the platform-wide UI redesign and its Front-End refactoring, enhancing user-facing and backoffice screens with consistency in UI and copy, with overwhelming client satisfaction
- Led the Front-End refactoring and UX overhaul for the Workflow Automations of the platform's Low-Code segment, utilizing a new node-based UI pattern, resulting in 53% increased usage
- Led the implementation of a pseudo-viewport component for rendering 9 possible layout views of our platform while ensuring full consistency in navigation between pages using them
- Led the UI/UX redesign and Front-End refactoring for the Low-code page components settings by using a detailed sidebar for a consistent experience, reducing usage friction by 65%
- Led the refactoring of a visual JSON Editor for API integration within Workflow Automations
- Vue, Nuxt, Vuex, StoryBook, Jest, Cypress, SCSS, Rails / Figma, Whimsical

Y Front-End Developer & UI/UX Designer @ Buser (Softbank) 1Y4M 09/2021 - 13/2022

- Led the Product Discovery and Front-End Development of a dynamic blog-like feature, yielding 60k SEO-optimized pages that elevated organic traffic from 500k to 2.5M within 10 months
- Developed the Front-End for the redesigned UX of our checkout page, making it into a single-page flow without a sign-up requirement, resulting in a 16% increase in conversion rate
- Optimized dozens of Design System Vue components with in-depth documentation, accessibilitybased unit testing, and shrank its build size by 30% by reducing unecessary JS dependencies
- Promoted best practices for scalable CSS across the organization, offering guidance and mentoring for all things related to styling
- Mentored interns via classes, assignments, code reviews, and pair programming opportunities
- Vue, Nuxt, Vuex, VuePress, Jest, SCSS, django / Figma, Miro

**DX** Contract Front-End Developer @ BxBlue (Y Combinator S17) 4M | 10/2020 - 02/2021

- Led the design and implemented the UX for a WebRTC video-contract feature, lowering esignature costs by allowing users to articulate contract terms displayed on-screen verbally
- React, Styled Components, Jest, Enzyme, SCSS, Rails / Figma

Front-End Developer @ Olist (SoftBank)

3M | 13/2019 - 04/2020

- Refactored multiple legacy client-side features into a new React-based Design System
- React, Styled Components, Styled System, REBASS, DOCZ, jQuery, SCSS, Django
- Front-End Developer & UI/UX Designer @ LABHacker 3Y8M | 04/2016 - 12/2019
- Led the Product Discovery, Design Sprint, UI Design and Front-End development of a tool for citizen input on law drafts with consensus datavis + text editor for lawmakers in 7 months
- Developed the Front-End for a public hearings pilot tool with crowd-ranking questions, having 55% adoption by the House of Representatives within 1 year, and institutionalized by 2024
- SES5+, jQuery, SCSS, RSCSS, BEM, Django / Figma, Miro

Part-time Web Development Intern @ Interlegis

2Y | 13/2013 - 13/2015

**CJR** Part-time Web Developer @ CJR (University of Brasilia)

1Y | 09/2013 - 09/2014